Shawe-Taylor mss., 1929-1995 LMC 1954
Lilly Library
Shawe-Taylor mss.
1929-1995
Lilly Library
Shawe-Taylor, Desmond.
LMC 1954
5 Boxes 5 standard
The Shawe-Taylor mss., 1929-1995, consists of the papers of Desmond Christopher Shawe-Taylor, 1907-1995.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 1999
Biographical Note
Desmond Christopher Shawe-Taylor, 1907-1995, English music critic, was born in Dublin, Ireland and educated at Oxford. Upon graduation he was employed by The Royal Geographical Society as assistant editor of "Geographical Journal." After a short stint there he began writing mostly literary criticism and occasional music-related articles for The Times, The Spectator and other periodicals. In 1939 he joined the Royal Artillery of the British Territorial Army and served his final two years, 1944-1945, as Captain in GIII Intelligence. He resumed his writing career after the war, this time with an emphasis on music. In 1945 he was retained as the music critic for the New Statesman and Nation, and then gramophone critic for The Observer, as well as writing occasional articles for other journals. From 1958 until his retirement in 1983 he was chief music critic of the Sunday Times. In addition, he made frequent broadcasts on BBC Home Service and Third Programmes about music, particularly opera, singing and gramophone records. Shawe-Taylor also has several books to his credit. He wrote Covent Garden (London: Max Parrish, 1948) and collaborated on The Record Guide (London: Collins, 1951) and The Record Year (London: Collins, [1953]) with Edward Sackville-West.
Scope and Contents
The Shawe-Taylor mss., 1929-1995, consists of the papers of Desmond Christopher Shawe-Taylor, 1907-1995. Correspondence is mainly with colleagues and friends. There is a large group of letters from John Francis Warre Rathbone which spans from their school years together to Rathbone's appointment as Secretary of the National Trust. Also present is an extensive series of letters, particularly through the war years, from Shawe-Taylor to Edward Sackville-West with whom he and Raymond Mortimer purchased a house, Long Crichel in Dorset, in 1944. Other correspondents include: H.M. Barnes, Ian Cosens, David Stacy Colman, Edward Dent, Emma Eames, Elena Gerhardt, William Rodes Moran, Raymond Mortimer, Ernest Newman, Frances Partridge, Andrew Porter, and Sir Michael Tippett.
Writings include typescripts, carbon copies, etc. of his articles, scripts, lectures, and his revised entries for The New Grove Dictionary of Music and Musicians that he was editing.
The Financial/legal materials consist primarily of bank statements from Lloyds Bank, and correspondence and statements from his investors.
The Photographs include many snapshots of friends, though they are principally unidentified. Also present are portraits of opera singers in costume.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: I. Correspondence; II. Writings; III. Financial/legal; IV. Photographs; V. Miscellaneous; and VI. Clippings.
Music --History and criticism.; Singers --Photographs.; Radio plays; Music; British Broadcasting Corporation.; British Broadcasting Corporation.; Shawe-Taylor, Desmond.; Shawe-Taylor, Desmond --Correspondence.; Sackville-West, Edward, Hon., 1901-1965.; Rathbone, John Francis Warre.
- Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Individual names with significant number of letters may have separate folders and are filed immediately after the folder in which they would have been included. Occasional copies of letters from Shawe-Taylor may be found throughout the correspondence, but are not listed.
  - Ackerley, John (Box 1)
  - Adams, Bill (Box 1)
  - Adprint Ltd., (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Agate, James (Box 1)
  - Ailes, Edgar H., Includes: two letters from Emma Eames and three letters from Mary Garden, all to Ailes. (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Aldeburgh Foundation (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Dick (Box 1)
  - Allen, William (Box 1)
  - Allgood, Sara (Sally) (Box 1)
  - Angel Records (Box 1)
  - Armendariz, Pablo (Box 1)
  - ARTIA (Box 1)
  - Asquith, Anthony (Box 1)
  - Asser, Michael (Box 1)
  - Ayrton, Michael (Box 1)
  - Baddeley, Colonel (Box 1)
    General
    see: Garrick Club
  - Bannerman, Betty (Box 1)
  - Barnes, H.M. (Jan), (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Bartley, Lucy (Box 1)
    see: The British Broadcasting Corporation
  - Belcantodisc (Box 1)
  - Berkeley, Lennox (Box 1)
  - Bicknell, J. David (Box 1)
    see: Electric & Musical Industries Limited
  - Blackham, Richard (Box 1)
    see: W. Schwann Inc., Publisher
  - Bliss, Arthur (Box 1)
  - Blom, Eric (Box 1)
    see: Grove
  - Bornoff, Jack (Box 1)
    see: International Music Council
  - Boswell, Ronald (Box 1)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Bridges-Adam, W. (Box 1)
  - The British Broadcasting Corporation., Includes press releases. (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - The British Council (Box 1)
  - The British Institute of Recorded Sound (Box 1)
  - Britten, Benjamin (Box 1)
  - Brook, Peter (Box 1)
  - Buchanan, George (Box 1)
  - Buckland, John (Box 1)
  - Campion, Paul (Box 1)
  - Caraman, Philip, S.J. (Box 1)
  - Cardus, Neville (Box 1)
  - Castillo, Manuel del (Box 1)
  - Cattanach, David (Box 1)
  - Cecil, David (Box 1)
  - Cecil, Jonathan (Box 1)
  - Clark, John (Box 1)
  - Colleran, Kate (Box 1)
  - Collins Publishers (Box 1)
  - Colman, (David) Stacy (Box 1)
  - Compton-Burnett, Ivy (Box 1)
  - Concert Associates, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Contact Publications Ltd. (Box 1)
  - Copland, Aaron (Box 1)
  - Cosens, Ian, (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Coveney, John (Box 1)
    see: Angel Records
  - Crabbie, Mrs. G.E. (Box 1)
  - Crozier, Eric (Box 1)
  - Crutchfield, Will (Box 1)
  - Cummings, David (Box 1)
  - Cunard, Nancy (Box 1)
  - Curtis Brown Ltd., (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Davies, Marfa Hudson (Chaliapin) (Box 1)
  - Deal, Edgar M. (Box 1)
  - Dennis, James (Box 1)
  - Dent, Edward (Box 1)
  - Desmond, Astra (Box 1)
  - Dolan, Peter F. (Box 1)
  - Draper, Ruth (Box 1)
  - Duff, Juliet (Box 1)
  - Eames, Emma, (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Eckstein, Pavel (Box 1)
  - Electric & Musical Industries Limited (Box 1)
  - EMI Music Archives (Box 1)
  - Engle, Marie (Box 1)
  - Esterson, Allen (Box 1)
  - Ewans, Michael (Box 1)
  - Exon, R.H.C. (Box 1)
  - Falconer, Graham (Box 1)
  - Fassett, Steve B. (Box 1)
  - Favia-Artsay, Aida (Box 1)
  - Feder, Susan (Box 1)
  - Finch, Rhona (Box 1)
    see: Opus 111
  - Forey, Edmund (Box 1)
  - Forster, E.M. (Box 1)
  - Foster, Addison, III (Box 1)
  - Franckenstein, Sir George (Box 1)
  - Frank, Roger W. (Box 1)
  - Frankenstein, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Frelinghuysen, Matilda E. (Box 1)
  - Garrick Club (Box 1)
  - Gate, Richard K. (Box 1)
  - Gerhard, Roberto (Box 1)
  - Gerhardt, Elena., Includes two photographs. (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Glyndebourne Festival Opera (Box 1)
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John (Box 1)
  - The Gramophone (Box 1)
  - Gregg Press Limited (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Eric C. (Box 1)
    see: Percy Lund Humphries & Co Ltd
  - Grey, Madeleine (Box 1)
  - Grove, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Grove's Dictionary of Music and Musicians (Box 1)
  - Hadfield, Tony (Box 1)
  - Hagman, Bertil (Box 1)
  - Hanley, James (Box 1)
  - Harewood, George Henry Hubert Lascelles, Earl of (Box 1)
  - Hart, Reginald M. (Box 1)
  - Heinitz, Tom (Box 1)
  - Henderson, Jack (Box 1)
  - Henstock, Michael E. (Box 1)
  - Henze, Hans Werner (Box 1)
  - Hirsch, Alice (Box 1)
    see: The Record Album
  - Hirsch, Henry (Box 1)
  - Hitchens, Ivon (Box 1)
  - Hodgkins, Frances (Box 1)
  - Holden, Frances (Box 1)
  - Holden, Frank (Box 1)
  - Holloway, Robin (Box 1)
  - Holt, Pier Luigi (Box 1)
  - Hone, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Hope-Wallace, Philip (Box 1)
  - Hopkins, J. (Box 1)
  - Howland, Robert (Box 1)
  - Hughes, J.M. (Box 1)
  - Hughes, Suzanne (Box 1)
    see: The British Council
  - Hutber, Diana (Box 1)
  - Hutchinson?, Mary (Box 1)
  - Ichihara, Yuzum, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - International Music Council (Box 1)
  - International Musicological Mozart Congress (Box 1)
    see: Eckstein, Pavel
  - Isherwood, Christopher (Box 1)
  - Istituto di Studi Verdiani (Box 1)
  - Jacobs, Arthur (Box 1)
  - Jebb, Julian (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Barbara J. (Box 1)
  - Jones, Parry (Box 1)
  - Kelly, Alan (Box 1)
  - Kilkelly, Mina (Box 1)
  - Klingsberg, Erwin (Box 1)
  - Končelíková, J. (Box 1)
    see: ARTIA
  - Lamb, Henry (Box 1)
  - Lander, Jack R. (Box 1)
  - Lauren, Janet R. (Box 1)
    see: Concert Associates, Inc.
  - Lee, Laurie (Box 1)
  - Lees-Milne, John (Box 1)
  - Lehmann, Lotte (Box 1)
  - Lehmann, Rosamond (Box 1)
  - Lewis, Suzanne (Box 1)
    see: EMI Music Archives
  - Liles, G. (Box 1)
  - Lochore, Don W. (Box 1)
  - Loewenberg, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Lussan, Zelie de (Box 1)
  - Macaulay, Rose (Box 1)
  - MacCarthy, Mary (Warre-Cornish) (Box 1)
  - MacNutt, Richard (Box 1)
    see: Richard MacNutt Limited
  - Madonna, Wanda (Box 1)
  - Martin, Kingsley (Box 1)
    see: The New Statesman and Nation
  - Maugham, W. Somerset (Box 1)
  - Maw, Nicholas (Box 1)
  - Maxwell-Arnot, Madeleine (Box 1)
  - McHardy, John (Box 1)
  - Medici, Mario (Box 1)
    see: Istituto di Studi Verdiani
  - Mellers, Wilfrid (Box 1)
  - Menuhin, Yehudi (Box 1)
  - Mitchell, John (Box 1)
  - Moberly, Bob (Box 1)
  - Moore, Maurice (Box 1)
  - Moran, William R., (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Mortimer, Raymond, (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Murdoch, Iris (Box 1)
  - The New Grove Dictionary of American Music (Box 1)
  - The New Grove Dictionary of Music & Musicians (Box 1)
  - The New Grove Dictionary of Music in the United States (Box 1)
  - The New Statesman and Nation (Box 1)
  - Newman, Ernest (Box 1)
  - Nicolson, Harold (Box 1)
  - Notcutt, Arthur (Box 1)
  - Notley, Frances (Mrs. Archer) (Box 1)
  - Ocampo, Victoria (Box 1)
  - O'Harra, Richard (Box 1)
  - Opus 111 (Box 1)
  - Orr, Robin (Box 1)
  - Oxford., Contains letters from various Oxford friends. (1 folder) (Box 1)
    See also: Colman, (David) Stacy
  - Partridge, Frances (Fanny) (Box 1)
  - Pattinson-Knight, C. (Box 1)
    see: Piccadilly Cinematograph Film Productions Limited
  - Pears, Sir Peter (Box 1)
  - Pearsall Smith, Logan (Box 1)
  - Pemberton, Christopher. (Box 1)
    Appended to Edward Sackville-West to Shawe-Taylor, July 3, 1965
  - Percy Lund Humphries & Co Ltd (Box 1)
  - Perry, David (Box 1)
  - The Physical Society (Box 1)
  - Piccadilly Cinematograph Film Productions Limited (Box 1)
  - Piper, Myfanwy (Box 1)
  - Pipkin, R. Keith (Box 1)
  - Platnauer, Maurice (Box 1)
  - Plomer, William (Box 1)
  - Pollak, K.A., (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Pollard, Anthony C. (Box 1)
    see: The Gramophone
  - Porter, Andrew, (8 folders) (Box 1)
  - Porter, Andrew, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Potter, Jeremy (Box 2)
    see: New Statesman & Nation
  - Powell, Peter (Box 2)
    see: Britten, Benjamin (postcard)
  - Price-Jones, G. (Box 2)
  - Prior, P.A. (Box 2)
  - Pritchett, Victor S. (Box 2)
  - Rainier, Priaulx (Box 2)
  - Ralston, William H. (Box 2)
  - Rathbone, Jack, (11 folders) (Box 2)
  - Reah, Allan J. (Box 2)
    see: Belcantodisc
  - The Record Album (Box 2)
  - Richard MacNutt Limited (Box 2)
  - Roche, David (Box 2)
  - Rodgers, Viola (Box 2)
  - Rodier, Harold (Box 2)
  - Rolland, Marie (neé Marie Kodachova; married Romain Rolland) (Box 2)
  - Rosado, Miguel A. (Box 2)
  - Rosenthal, Harold (Box 2)
  - Ross, A.G. (Box 2)
  - Royal Opera House (Box 2)
  - Rubbra, Edmund (Box 2)
  - Rubra, G.W. (Box 2)
  - Sackville-West, Edward: (Box 2)
    - From Shawe-Taylor., (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - To Shawe-Taylor., (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Sackville-West, Vita (Box 2)
  - Sadie, Stanley (Box 2)
  - Sands, Ethel (Box 2)
  - Sargent, Sir Malcolm (Box 2)
  - Saul, Patrick (Box 2)
    see: The British Institute of Recorded Sound
  - Schonberg, Harold C(harles) (Box 2)
  - Schumann, Elisabeth., Includes two photos. (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Searle, Humphrey (Box 2)
  - Seiber, Matyas (Box 2)
  - Seltsam, William H. (Box 2)
  - Shawe-Taylor, Desmond (Box 2)
    See also: Sackville-West, Edward.
    - Four postcards to his mother, Apr. 1934 (Box 2)
    - one postcard to Denis Rickett, July 20, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Shawe-Taylor, Nora (Box 2)
  - Shone, Richard (Box 2)
  - Sieskind, W.G. (Box 2)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc. Publishers (Box 2)
  - Simon, Henry W. (Box 2)
    see: Simon and Schuster, Inc. Publishers
  - Simpson, Harold (Box 2)
  - Slobodskaya, Oda (Box 2)
  - Smith, Jimmie (Box 2)
  - Smith, R. Geoffrey (Box 2)
    see: W.S. Cowell Ltd.
  - Sniffin, C. Merwin (Box 2)
  - Sorabji, Kaikhosru Shapurji (Box 2)
  - Souzay, Gâerard (Box 2)
  - Sparks, Ronald L. (Box 2)
  - Spicer, H.E. (Box 2)
  - Stein, Erwin (Box 2)
  - Stern, Fred (Box 2)
  - Stratton, John (Box 2)
  - Tavener, John (Box 2)
  - Tavernier, René (Box 2)
  - Templer, Cecil (Box 2)
  - Tennant, Stephen (Box 2)
  - Teyte, Maggie (Box 2)
  - Tippett, Sir Michael (Box 2)
  - Tonks, Henry (Box 2)
  - Tooley, John (Box 2)
    see: Royal Opera House
  - Toynbee, Philip (Box 2)
    see: Contact Publications Ltd.
  - Turnell, Douglas (Box 2)
  - Tutt, Robin (Box 2)
  - Union of Czechoslavak Composers (Box 2)
  - United States Information Service. Concerns Shawe-Taylor's application for the Smith-Mundt leader program., (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Vanni-Marcoux., Includes one photograph. (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Vaughan Williams, Ralph (Box 2)
  - Veale, John (Box 2)
  - Verlag Rolf Putziger (Box 2)
  - Villaseñor W., Lorenzo (Box 2)
  - Villiers, C.G.S. de (Box 2)
  - Vogue (Box 2)
  - W. Schwann Inc., Publisher (Box 2)
  - W.S. Cowell Ltd. (Box 2)
  - Watkins, Vernon (Box 2)
  - Weaver, William (Box 2)
  - Webber, Frankie (Box 2)
  - Weidenfeld, A.G. (Box 2)
  - Weingartner, F. (Box 2)
  - Welitsch, Ljuba, Includes one photograph (Box 2)
  - Wescott, Glenway (Box 2)
  - Whettam, Graham (Box 2)
  - William Lennard Concerts (Box 2)
    see: Mitchell, John
  - Williams, Frank F. (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Angus (Box 2)
  - Wordsworth, William D. (Box 2)
  - The Worshipful Company of Musicians (Box 2)
  - Wyler, Michael (Box 2)
  - Young, Gerard Mackworth (Box 2)
  - Personal ads correspondence. From members of the homosexual community instigated by personal ads placed in Exchange & Mart, Film and Filming, etc. by Shawe-Taylor in, 1943; 1946; 1954; 1965; Includes unpublished novel. (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - First names only/illegible signatures., (1 folder) (Box 2)
- Writings
  Organized into the following subseries: articles; books; Grove's; lectures; scripts; notebooks.
  - Articles (Box 2)
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Beno Blachut - tenor., photocopy, 5 p. (Box 2)
    - Benjamin Britten., holograph, 11 p.; two carbon typescripts, 7 p. each; one holograph of an additional article, 31 p.; holograph of an outline, 6 p. (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Bernard Shaw as Music Critic., two carbon typescripts, 63 p. and 35 p. (Box 2)
    - Extending the Opera Repertory., corrected printer's copy, 8 p. (Box 2)
    - Manon Lescaut: The Novel and the Operas., holograph, 31 p. (Box 2)
    - Mathis der Maler., holograph, 10 p. (Box 2)
    - The Music of Roberto Gerhard., holograph, 17 p. (Box 2)
    - Musical Chaos., carbon typescript, 9 p. (incomplete) (Box 2)
    - The Musical Theatre in London Since 1947., carbon typescript, 5 p. (Box 2)
    - New Music., galley (Box 2)
    - Noel Mewton-Wood., holograph, 6 p. (Box 2)
    - A Nordic Diary., carbon typescript, 4 p. (incomplete) on verso of: Musical Chaos (Box 2)
    - The Operas of Leoš Janáček., Proof (Box 2)
    - An Outburst of Opera., carbon typescript, 5 p. (Box 2)
    - Personal Preference., carbon typescript, 6 p. (Box 2)
    - An Urgent Appeal to Every Reader of the Gramophone., carbon typescript, 7 p. (Box 2)
    - Vaughan Williams., holograph, 9 p. (Box 2)
    - What Matters Most in Opera?, typescript, 7 p. (Box 2)
    - [untitled record reviews]., carbon typescript and mimeograph, 6 p. (Box 2)
  - Books (Box 2)
    - Covent Garden., Contains: Bibliography, several draft pages, an insert, etc. (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Grove's (Box 2)
    - Research and proofs for entries in New Grove Dictionary of Music and Musicians, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - (cont.), (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Lectures (Box 3)
    - Benjamin Britten., typescript, 12 p. (Box 3)
    - Mozart as Opera Composer., typescript, 11 p. (Box 3)
    - Style in the Singing of Mozart., holograph, 5 p.; typescript, 9 p.; printed syllabus from the University of London (1953-1954) which includes this title (Box 3)
    - Yvette Guilbert. Given, Apr. 19, 1980; typescript, 16 p. and various research materials. (Box 3)
  - Scripts. (Box 3)
    Mostly BBC broadcast scripts. Transmission date given, when known.
    - Adelina Patti (1843-1919)., mimeograph, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Arabella., carbon typescript, 10 p. (Box 3)
    - The Art of Beno Blachut. For Radio 3, May 20, 1977; mimeograph, 12 p. (Box 3)
    - The Art of Ivan Kozlovsky. Recorded, Jan. 9, 1979; typescript, 8 p. (Box 3)
    - The Art of Lotte Lehmann. For BBC World Sevice, recorded, Mar. 28, 1972; mimeograph, 7 p. (Box 3)
    - Beniamino Gigli (1)., Apr. 19, 1971; mimeograph, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Benjamin Britten: A Retrospective Survey. For BBC Home Service, Nov. 21, 1963; carbon typescript, 12 p. and mimeograph, 18 p. (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - Benjamin Britten and English Poetry., typescript and carbon typescript, 24 p. each. (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - La Cenerentola and Its Interpreters., photocopy, 5 p. (Box 3)
    - Changing Styles in Mozart Singing., typescript, 12 p. and carbon typescript, 11 p. (Box 3)
    - Characterisation in Mozart's Operas: 1 – Con Giovanni. For BBC Third Programme, Apr. 22, 1948; carbon typescript (Box 3)
    - Characterisation in Mozart's Operas: 2 – The Marriage of Figaro. For BBC Third Programme, Apr. 29, 1948; two typescripts and carbon typescript, 5 p. each (Box 3)
    - The Classical Style by Charles Rosen. Book review by Shawe-Taylor., mimeograph, 8 p. (Box 3)
    - Conchita Supervia (5)., May 18, 1971; carbon typescript, 5 p.; mimeograph, 7 p.; and 3 p. of notes (Box 3)
    - Conchita Supervia and Rossini., carbon typescript, 9 p. (Box 3)
    - Discovering Opera. Series of six programs, Oct.-Nov. 1945; typescripts. 10 p., 9 p., 8 p., 7 p., 7 p., 8 p. (Box 3)
    - Dvorak's The Jacobin., typescript, 3 p. (Box 3)
    - Enrico Caruso (1873-1921). For Music Magazine, Feb. 20, 1973; carbon typescript 4 p.;mimeograph, 8 p. and one page of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Feodor Chaliapin (1873-1938). For Music Magazine, Feb. 6, 1973; mimeograph, 8 p. (Box 3)
    - The First Version of Fidelio., typescript, 5 p. (Box 3)
    - The Flying Dutchman. For BBC Home Service, Jan. 19, 1961; carbon typescript, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - Four Great Singers. For BBC Third Programme, Sept.-Oct. 1947; 1 folder (Box 3)
      - 1. Nellie Melba (1859-1931)., two typescripts, 6 p. and 7 p. (Box 3)
      - 2. Ernestine Schumann-Heink (1861-1936)., two typescripts, 6 p. and 5 p.; carbon typescript, 6 p. (Box 3)
      - 3. John McCormack., typescript, 5 p.; carbon typescript, 6 p.; one page of discography (Box 3)
      - 4. Pol Plançon (1854-1914)., typescript, 6 p.; carbon typescript, 6 p.; typescript, with holograph sections, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Frida Leider and Jahhie Teyte: Two Birthday Tributes., mimeograph, 7 p. and 4 p. of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Frida Leider in Some of Famous Roles.(series: Historic Performances on Record). For BBC Third Programme, Mar. 21, 1964; mimeograph, 7pp (Box 3)
    - Fritz Kreisler (1875-1962)., Jan. 18, 1972; mimeograph, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Gigli. For BBC Home Service: (Box 3)
      - Dec. 25, 1957, carbon typescript, 5 p. (Box 3)
      - Mar. 17, 1958, typescript, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Giovanni Martinelli. For BBC Home Service, Aug. 9, 1960; carbon typescript, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Handel's Messiah., photocopy, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - The Interpreters of Gluck's Orpheus. For BBC Radio 3, Jan. 31, 1971; mimeograph, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Ivor Newton. For Music Magazine, Dec. 10, 1972; carbon typescript, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - Janacek's Jenufa. For Music Weekly, Mar. 2, 1975; mimeograph, 5 p. (Box 3)
    - Janacek's Operas. For BBC Third Programme, Apr. 13, 1959; mimeograph, 17 p. (Box 3)
    - Kirsten Flagstad., typescript, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - Lakmé: Interval Talk., Aug. 22, 1971; photocopy, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - Lucia di Lammermoor and its Interpreters., typescript, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - Manon and its Interpreters., photocopy, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - Mary Garden (1874-1967)., mimeograph, 5 p. and 3 p. of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Mattia Battistini. Famous Singers series. For BBC Third Programme, Oct. 2, 1956; mimeograph, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - A Melba Biography, book review., carbon typescript, 3 p.; mimeograph, 6 p.; and one page of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - The Metropolitan Opera. For BBC Third Programme, Oct. 7, 1954; two carbon typescripts, 10 p. each (Box 3)
    - Music-Lovers' Calendar [Verdi's early operas]. For BBC Home Service, Oct. 1, 1944; carbon typescript, 7 p. (Box 3)
    - Music Magazine extracts:, (1 folder) (Box 3)
      - [L'Enfant et les Sortilèges], Dec. 12, 1948; typescript (Box 3)
      - [review of biography of Enrico Caruso, by T.R. Ybarra], Feb. 27, 1955; carbon typescript (Box 3)
      - [review of book Leos Janacek, His Life and Works, translated from the Czech of Jaroslav Vogel by Geraldine Thomsen-Muchová], June 23, 1963; mimeograph (Box 3)
      - [Donizetti], undated, typescript (Box 3)
    - Music of the Western Masters. For BBC Eastern Service, (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - Verdi and Rossini, Nov. 12, [1947]; typescript, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Gluck, Nov. 19, [1947]; typescript, 5 p. (Box 3)
    - Johann Strauss, Jan. 21, 1948; typescript, 4 p.; carbon typescript, 5 p. (Box 3)
    - Musical Profile: Geraldine Farrar. Pre-recorded, May 24, 1967; typescript, 4 p.; carbon typescript, 6 p.; and two pages of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - On Wings of Song. For BBC Home Service, Sept. 24, 1956; typescript, carbon typescript, 8 p. each and one page of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Scenes from Bellini's Opera La Sonnambula. For BBC Home Service, Jan. 26, 1960; mimeograph, 5 p. and two pages of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Siegfried – Narration., carbon typescript, 7 p. (Box 3)
    - Singer and Accompanist: book review. For Music Magazine., carbon typescript, 3 p.; mimeograph, 6 p.; and one page of holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Sounds of Music. Two part programme for BBC Third Programme., June 20, 1966; two mimeographs, 11 p. and 15 p.; three pages of holograph notes; The Acoustics of Concert Halls, by Peter Parkin, mimeograph, 19 p. (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - Studies in Interpretation: Three talks. For BBC Third Programme, May 18, 1950; Nove 16, 1950; Nov. 23, 1950; mimeographs, 8 p., 6 p., 6 p. (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - Til Eulenspiegel. For BBC Light Programme, July 8, 1946; carbon typescript, 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Il Trovatore and its Interpreters. For Music Magazine., 6 p. (Box 3)
    - Turandot and the Gramophone. For Radio Three, Mar. 9, 1972; carbon typescript, 4 p.; and mimeograph, 5 p. (Box 3)
    - The Two Ariadnes. For BBC Third Programme, Aug, 21, 1950; mimeograph, 7 p. (Box 3)
    - A Vanished Style., typescript, 2 p. (Box 3)
    - Voice and Style. For BBC Third Programme. Three talks, Oct.-Nov. 1951; (1 folder) (Box 3)
      - 1. Giovanni Martinelli., two mimeographs, 11 p. each (Box 3)
      - 2. Conchita Supervia., two mimeographs, 10 p. each (Box 3)
      - 3. Giuseppe de Luca., mimeograph, 8 p. (Box 3)
    - Voice and Style. For BBC Third Programme. Four talks, Feb. 1953; (1 folder) (Box 3)
      - 1. L'Eloge des Vieux., two mimeographs, 7 p. each (Box 3)
      - 2. A Vanished Style., mimeograph, 7 p. (Box 3)
      - 3. The Voice of France., mimeograph, 7 p. (Box 3)